{"tossups": [{"question": "King Godfred built the Danevirke as a defense against this ruler, and later this ruler concluded the Treaty of Heiligen with the Hemming. This ruler, who died of pleurisy, was succeeded by his son Louis the Pious, and three of his grandsons divided his empire in the Treaty of Verdun. This ruler, who was advised by Alcuin of York, was crowned on Christmas Day by Leo III as Imperator Romanorum. For ten points, name this King of the Franks who was the first Holy Roman Emperor.", "answer": "<b> Charlemagne</b> (or<b> Charles I</b> or<b> Carolus Magnus</b>)", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {}, {}, {"question": "The documentary<em> An Unreasonable Man</em> examined this man, whose study of the Chevy Corvair led him to advocate for seat belts and other basic safety features. He ran on a Presidential ticket with Winona LaDuke in a third party candidacy that some feel cost Al Gore the 2000 election. For ten points, name this consumer activist and Green Party politician who wrote<em> Unsafe at Any Speed</em>.", "answer": "Ralph<b> Nader</b>", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {}, {}, {"question": "Land acquired to create this city was bought from William Blaxton, and it built the first American public school, its Latin School, in 1635. This capital of the Dominion of New England was the site of an incident on King Street involving snowballs and Redcoats that led to the death of Crispus Attacks. For ten points, name this capital of Massachusetts, the site of a 1770 massacre.", "answer": "<b> Boston</b>", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {}, {"question": "In one wartime film, this character wakes up from a dream where he had to work in a Nazi factory tightening shells. This star of<em> Der Fuhrer\u2019s Face</em> has an uncle who is the richest character in their fictional universe .This character wears a sailor\u2019s outfit with a red bow tie but no pants. This character\u2019s nephews are Huey, Dewey, and Louie. For ten points, name this Disney-created duck.", "answer": "<b> Donald</b> Duck", "metadata": "Fine Arts - Other Fine Arts - Misc Arts"}, {"question": "One memorial to this policy is located on Eagle Harbor on Bainbridge Island. Those affected by it were asked 28 questions; the last two were the \u201cloyalty questionnaire.\u201d Begun by Executive Order 9066, this event was upheld by the Supreme Court in<em> Korematsu v. U.S.</em> For ten points, the United States carried out what World War II-era process of deporting Asian-Americans to concentration camps?", "answer": "<b> Japanese</b>(-American)<b> internment</b> <b>Second Quarter</b>", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "This kingdom defeated King Zwide [zwee-day] by dividing his army at the Mhlatuze [m-hlah-TOO-zay] River. Mpande ruled this kingdom after surviving Dingane\u2019s purges; Mpande\u2019s son, Cetshwayo [keht-SHWAH-yoh], led this empire to an early victory at Isandlwana [ee-son-dull-WAH-nah] over the British before losing its capital, Ulundi, in 1879. For ten points, name this south African kingdom, led in the early 19th century by Shaka.", "answer": "<b> Zulu</b> Kingdom or Empire", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {}, {}, {}, {"question": "This man noted that \u201cThe clock cannot be set back. You cannot restore Central Europe to 1870\u201d in a work that lamented Clemenceau\u2019s \u201cCarthaginian Peace.\u201d This author of<em> The Economic Consequences</em> <em>of the Peace</em> argued that natural business cycles should be moderated by government intervention. For ten points, name this British economist who outlined modern macroeconomics with his<em> General Theory</em> <em>of Employment, Interest, and Money</em>.", "answer": "John Maynard<b> Keynes</b>", "metadata": "Social Science - Social Science - Economics"}, {}, {"question": "Tomas Cloma established the Free Territory of Freedomland in this body of water. The \u201cnine-dotted line\u201d designates one country\u2019s territorial claims in this body of water. Several countries dispute the potential oil reserves of this body of water\u2019s Paracel and Spratly Islands. For ten points, name this body of water that borders the Philippines, Vietnam, and a large Asian country.", "answer": "<b> South China</b> Sea [do not accept \u201cEast China Sea\u201d]", "metadata": "Geography - Geography"}, {}, {"question": "Supposedly, prior to this battle, Cyrsillus and his wife were stoned for suggesting surrender. Washed up sailors were slaughtered on Psyttaleia [sit-uh-LYE-uh] by Aristides [air-uh-STY-dees], and a throne was erected for the losing commander to watch the battle. This battle vindicated the \u201cwooden walls\u201dof Themistocles, who advocated abandoning Athens prior to this battle. The battles of Artemisium and Thermopylae were fought prior to, for ten points, what naval battle, a victory for the allied Greeks over Xerxes I?", "answer": "Battle of<b> Salamis</b>", "metadata": "History - Ancient History"}, {}, {"question": "This year saw the National Liberal party push Frederick VII to create a new constitution, which made him share power with the Rigsdag. This year saw William O\u2019Brien lead the Young Irelander Rebellion, and the March Revolution in this year in Germany led to the Frankfurt Assembly offering the German crown to Wilhelm IV. Klemens von Metternich resigned as Chancellor of Austria in this year, which saw the establishment of the French Second Republic. For ten points, name this year that saw multiple revolutions against various European Governments.", "answer": "<b> 1848</b>", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {}, {}, {}, {"question": "This city was the capital of a sultanate that, after losing the Battle of Marj Dabiq, was conquered in 1517 by Selim I. Muhammad Ali Pasha westernized this former capital of the Mamluk sultanate and current capital of the Arab League. Port Said [sai-EED] is north of, and the Suez Canal is east of, for ten points, what city whose outskirts are home to the Great Pyramid of Giza, the capital of Egypt?", "answer": "<b> Cairo </b>", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {}, {"question": "<b>After being defeated in World War I, this country lost much of its land in the Treaty of Trianon, but some of that land was later restored by Austria in the First Vienna Award. The Nazi-backed (+) Arrow Cross Party ended this country\u2019s \u201cregency\u201d after it overthrew Miklos (*)</b> Horthy. In the aftermath of World War II, this country was occupied by the Soviet Union, which later put down this country\u2019s 1956 Revolution. For ten points, name this European country with capital Budapest.", "answer": "<b> Hungary</b>", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {"question": "<b>John Aaron rationed battery power during this event. Ken Mattingly was supposed to</b> <b>have participated in this event but was unable due to (+)</b> <b>German Measles, while Fred</b> <b>Haise suffered a serious urinary tract infection during it. During this event, the service (*) </b> module\u2019s number 2 oxygen tank suffered a failure, causing Jack Swigert and Jim Lovell to report\u201cHouston, we\u2019ve had a problem\u201d. For ten points, name this NASA mission whose moon landing was aborted but which returned safely to Earth.", "answer": "<b> Apollo 13</b>", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {}, {}, {}, {}, {"question": "<b>This agreement resolved the underlying dispute of Cresap\u2019s War. David Rittenhouse and Andrew Ellicott finished mapping this agreement after Iroquois guides refused to cross into</b> <b>(+)</b> <b>Lenape territory. It includes a 12-mile arc around New Castle, outside of which lies a</b> <b>Lenape territory. It includes a 12-mile arc around New Castle, outside of which lies a</b> <b>\u201cwedge\u201d once claimed by both (*)</b> <b>\u201cwedge\u201d once claimed by both (*)</b> Delaware and Pennsylvania. This agreement is named for the two British surveyors who mapped it. For ten points, name this line geographically separating Maryland and Pennsylvania, which symbolically separated free Northern states from slave-owning Southern states.", "answer": "<b> Mason-Dixon</b> line (prompt on descriptions of \u201cthe border between any or all of Pennsylvania, Maryland, and Delaware\u201d)", "metadata": "Geography - Geography"}, {"question": "<b>One battle at this site saw Bruno von Mudra and Karl von Eimen lead assaults on the French Fourth army under Henri Gouraud. Another battle here was preceded by the</b> <b>replacement of Charles (+)</b> <b>Lanzerac with Louis d\u2019Esprey for \u201clacking offensive spirit.\u201d</b> <b>Lanzerac with Louis d\u2019Esprey for \u201clacking offensive spirit.\u201d</b> <b>After that battle, Helmuth (*)</b> <b>After that battle, Helmuth (*)</b> Von Moltke proclaimed \u201cMajesty, we have lost the war\u201d and abandoned the Schlieffen plan. Taxicabs brought soldiers to, for ten points, what site of an early Allied victory in WW1 that saved Paris?", "answer": "(Battles of the)<b> Marne</b> River  (1) <b>Writing under the name \u201cHercules,\u201d Jesse Hawley put forth an idea for this</b> <b>object, which was laid out by James Geddes and Benjamin Wright. The \u201cBucktails\u201d</b> <b>were annoyed with Governor (+)</b> <b>DeWitt Clinton over this object, which connected</b> <b>the Mohawk and Hudson rivers and ran from (*)</b> Albany to Buffalo. For ten points, name this canal built in New York during the early 19th century. ANSWER:<b> Erie</b> Canal", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {}], "bonuses": []}